nextraq.com 2019-12-06

# Privacy Policy - NexTraq

NexTraq LLC (“ _Company_ ,” “ _we_ ” or “ _us_ ”) is committed to protecting your privacy.  This Privacy Policy explains how the Company collects, uses, and shares the personal information we collect from visitors to our Company websites or users of the NexTraq services (“Services”), where the applicable terms and conditions for our Services (“Terms of Service”) reference this Privacy Policy.  For specific information about how we collect and use information collected from our customers, customers’ end-users, or on our customers’ behalf during the provision of our Services, please see “Customer Data,” below. By accessing or using our Company websites and Services, you signify that you have read, understood and agree to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy and our applicable Terms of Service.

  1.  ********Types of Information We Collect and How We Collect It****

You may view our Company websites without providing any personal information (other than information collected automatically as identified in the section entitled “How We Use Cookies and Other Tracking Technology”).  We may collect personal information that you provide to us when you set up an account, engage with our Services, sign up for our newsletter, or communicate with us. For example, we may request your personal information (e.g., name, postal address, email address, telephone number, and payment information) or your applicable business information when you register for an account to purchase our Services. We collect information you may provide when providing content or commentary on our blog, connecting with us on social media and other similar interactions (“ _User Content_ ”). Please note that User Content is published on our websites and will be viewable by the public. From time to time, we may also obtain information from other sources, such as third party information providers, or through mergers and acquisitions, and combine this with information previously collected. In these cases, our Privacy Policy governs the handling of the combined personal information.

We use this information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of our websites and Services, as well as to communicate directly with you, such as to respond to your inquiries, to send you newsletters or email messages about products and services that may be of interest to you.  We may also send you company-related emails or messages (e.g., account verification, billing confirmation, changes or updates to features of the Services, technical and security notices). For more information about your communication preferences, see “Control Over Your Information” below.

  2.  ********How We Use Cookies and Other Tracking Technology****

Like most websites and online services, we and certain of our third party providers may collect certain types of usage information automatically when you visit our websites, read our emails, or otherwise engage with us. We typically collect this information through a variety of tracking technologies, including cookies, web beacons, Flash cookies (locally stored objects), embedded scripts, location-identifying technologies, and similar technology (collectively, “tracking technologies”).  These tracking technologies collect information about how you use our websites (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions you take on our websites), information about your browser and online usage patterns (e.g., IP address, browser type, browser language, referring / exit pages and URLs, pages viewed, whether you opened an email , links clicked), and information about the device(s) you use to access our websites (e.g., mobile device identifier, mobile carrier, device type, model and manufacturer, mobile device operating system brand and model, and depending on your mobile device settings, your geographical location data (which could include GPS coordinates (e.g. latitude and/or longitude) or similar information regarding the location of your mobile device), or we may be able to approximate a device’s location by analyzing other information, like an IP address.  We, or our third party providers, may link your various devices so that content you see on one device can result in relevant content displayed on another device (which may include marketing information related to products or services that may be of interest to you)*, and so that we may recognize and contact you on the various devices you may use.  We may also collect analytics data, or use third party analytics tools, to help us measure traffic and usage of the Services. Although we do our best to honor the privacy preferences of our visitors, the Services are not configured to respond to Do Not Track signals from your browser.

We may use the data collected through tracking technologies to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit our websites; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information, including content (which may include marketing information related to products or services that may be of interest to you)*; (c) identify you across multiple devices; (d) provide and monitor the effectiveness of our websites and Services; (e) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, usage, and demographic patterns on our websites; (f) diagnose or fix technology problems; and (g) otherwise to plan for and enhance our websites and Services.

If you would prefer not to accept cookies, most browsers will allow you to: (i) change your browser settings to notify you when you receive a cookie, which lets you choose whether or not to accept it; (ii) disable existing cookies; or (iii) set your browser to automatically reject cookies.  Please note that doing so may negatively impact your experience using our websites, as some features on our websites may not work properly.  Depending on your mobile device and operating system, you may not be able to delete or block all cookies.  You may also set your e-mail options to prevent the automatic downloading of images that may contain technologies that would allow us to know whether you have accessed our e-mail and performed certain functions with it. Deleting cookies does not delete Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash objects and HTML5. You can learn more about Flash objects – including how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies – on Adobe’s website. If you choose to delete Flash objects from our sites, then you may not be able to access and use all or part of the sites or benefit from the information and services offered.

 _ _*For more information about our use of tracking technologies to display marketing information to you, please see “Third Party Tracking and Online Advertising” below__.

We use certain types of cookies which are “Strictly Necessary” or “Functional” cookies.  Please note that if you elect not to receive cookies, certain features or functionality of the Services which depend on Strictly Necessary Cookies or Functional Cookies may not function properly.

Strictly Necessary cookies are cookies that are indispensable due to the fact that the functionality of the Services is contingent on their existence.  The Strictly Necessary cookies do not conserve information once you leave the site. They permit, for example, to identify the terminals to dispatch the communication, to assign numbers to the data “packets” in order to dispatch them in the requested order, and to detect transmission errors or data loss.

Functional cookies are used exclusively for providing an electronic communication service at the request of the internet user.  The information is conserved beyond your browsing session on the internet website, and can be transmitted to partners, uniquely for means of supplying provisions necessary to the services. These can be, for example, cookies that save the preferences of the user such as language preference of the user, cookies that save a “user session”, or cookies that provide a “virtual shopping basket”.

  3.  ********How We Share Personal Information****

We may share your personal information in the instances described below, in each case subject to any relevant restrictions of applicable law (which may include providing you with the opportunity to opt out of or object to such sharing where such a right is provided under applicable law). For further information on your choices regarding your information, see “Control Over Your Information.”

We may share your personal information with third party providers or business partners who help us deliver or improve our websites and Services or who perform services on our behalf.  These services may include: identifying and serving advertisements that may be of interest to you, processing payments, sending postal mail, providing back-office services, or measuring site traffic.

We may share your information with third parties who may send you information about products and services you may enjoy. **** ****

We may aggregate, or anonymize, and then share that aggregated or anonymized information with third parties, including data brokers and other business partners, for our business purposes.

We may share or disclose your personal information if we determine, in our sole discretion, that such action is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with the law, regulatory requirements or the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) if we reasonably believe disclosure is necessary to prevent harm or financial loss, or in connection with detecting or preventing fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity, (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property or personal safety of the company, our employees, customers or others, and/or (d) to enforce our Terms of Service.

We may share with our affiliates (i.e., any corporation or other business entity which controls, or is controlled by, or is under common control with NexTraq).  The terms “control” and “controlled by” as used with respect to any entity, means the ownership, directly or indirectly, of a majority of the assets or voting stock of such entity.  These companies will use your personal information in the same way as we can under this Privacy Policy.

We reserve the right to transfer any information we collect in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including any shares in the company) or any portion or combination of our products, services, businesses and/or assets. Should such a transaction occur (whether a divestiture, merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, reorganization, liquidation, or similar transaction or proceeding), we will use reasonable efforts to ensure that any transferred information is treated in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.

  4.  ********Customer Data****

“Customer” means a party that has entered into a separate agreement to receive Services from NexTraq (a “Customer Agreement”), and “End-User” means an end-user of such Customer as defined in the related Customer Agreement.  In providing our Services, we may collect information about our Customers and End-Users associated with our Customers’ use of the Services.  This data is governed by our Customer Agreements with our Customers and by the terms of this Privacy Policy, but if these provisions conflict with the terms of our Customer Agreement, the Customer Agreement shall govern.

Our Customers may upload data to our Services or permit us to collect or access information on our Customers’ behalf, which may include personal information or other data about our Customer or our Customers’ End-Users (all of which we call “Customer Data”). Customer Data is owned and controlled by our Customers, and we collect and process Customer Data in accordance with our agreements with our Customers.

Depending on the functionality and Services purchased by a Customer, we may also collect information and data generated by a vehicle mounted wireless tracking device used in connection with our vehicle tracking application and service (“Tracking Device”), including geolocation, telemetry and movement data, associated with a specific vehicle (“Fleet Data”) driven by End-User. Our Customer is solely responsible for the placement of each Tracking Device and the corresponding collection of Fleet Data associated with the vehicle in which the Tracking Device is placed, and for compliance with all laws and best practices associated with the collection of Fleet Data, including providing notice to and obtaining consents from End-Users, if necessary for such collection. We may associate Fleet Data with Customer Data according to the settings and functionality of the Services utilized by the Customer. We collect and process Fleet Data in accordance with our Customer Agreements.

Further, depending on the functionality and Services purchased by a Customer, the Customer may direct End-Users (for example, Customer employees or drivers) to download and utilize our mobile application (“App”). If you download and use the App from a personal device, we may collect certain information about you, your device, your location, and your usage of the App. For example, we collect your user login and any personal information you or our Customer associate with the account, a mobile device identifier and other information associated with the mobile device, such as the make and model of the device and operating system and device phone number, and we may associate this information with Customer Data and Fleet Data.  We consider information we collect from your use of the App to be Customer Data, which we collect and process in accordance with our agreements with our Customers.

Please address all questions relating to the collection and use of Customer Data and/or Fleet Data to the Customer responsible for the account.

  5.  ********Control Over Your Information****

 _Email Communications_. From time to time, we may send you emails regarding updates to our websites, products or services, notices about our organization, or information about products/services we offer (or promotional offers from third parties) that we think may be of interest to you. If you wish to unsubscribe from such emails, simply click the “unsubscribe link” provided at the bottom of the email communication. Note that you cannot unsubscribe from certain company-related email communications (e.g., account verification, confirmations of transactions, technical or legal notices).

 _Modifying Account Information_. If you have an online account with us, you have the ability to modify certain information in your account (e.g., your contact information) through “profile,” “account,” “settings,” or “preferences” options provided on the Services. If you have any questions about modifying or updating any information in your account, please contact us as set forth in the “Contact Us” section below. Please note that NexTraq does not own or control the Customer Data submitted to or collected by our Services by or on behalf of our Customers, and NexTraq cannot modify or delete Customer Data except at the request of our Customer, or as permitted by our Customer Agreements.

  6.  ********Third Party Tracking and Online Advertising****

We may from time to time participate in interest-based advertising and use third party advertising companies to serve you marketing content based on use of the Services.  We may permit third party online advertising networks, social media companies and other third party services, to collect information about your use of our websites over time so that they may play or display ads on our websites, on other websites, apps or services you may use, and on other devices you may use.  Typically, though not always, the information we share is provided through cookies or similar tracking technologies, which recognize the device you are using and collect information, including click stream information, browser type, time and date you visited a website and other information. We may also share a common account identifier (such as an email address or user ID) to help us identify you across devices. We and our third party providers use this information to make the advertisements you see online more relevant to your interests.

As noted above, depending on your browser or mobile device, you may be able set your browser to delete or notify you of cookies and other tracking technology by actively managing the settings on your browser or mobile device. You may also be able to limit interest-based advertising through the settings on your mobile device by selecting “limit ad tracking” (iOS) or “opt-out of interest based ads” (Android). To learn more about interest-based advertising and how you may be able to opt-out of some of this advertising, you may wish to visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s online resources, at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>, and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance’s resources at [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).  Some of these opt-outs may not be effective unless your browser is set to accept cookies. Furthermore, if you use a different device, change browsers or delete the opt-out cookie, you may need to perform the opt-out task again.

  7.  ********Data Protection and Security****

 _Data Retention:_   We maintain standard data retention policies in the ordinary course of our business based on the type and nature of data collected and the purposes for which it is collected and/or used.  We will retain your information for so long as you are a customer and/or are otherwise using the Services, and afterwards in accordance with our ordinary data retention policies then in effect.  Following termination or deactivation of your account, we may also retain information for a commercially reasonable time for recordkeeping, audit or other purposes. Any Customer Data that we have access to shall be retained, stored, or deleted according to our Customer Agreements. Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, we may retain information where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

 _Data storage and transfer_ :  Your information may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which we or our subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities.  If you are located in the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction, and you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which we or our parent, subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

 _Keeping information safe_ :  We care about the security of your information and uses commercially reasonable physical, technical and organizational measures designed to preserve the integrity and security of all information we collect.  However, no security system is impenetrable, and we cannot guarantee the security of our systems 100%. In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify our Customers whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations.   The safety and security of your information also depends on you.  Where you have chosen a password to access the Services, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.  We ask that you not share this password with anyone.  Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure.  Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted via our Services.  Any transmission of personal information is done at your own risk.  We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Services.

Our obligations with respect Customer Data are defined in our Customer Agreements. Each Customer will remain responsible for the privacy and security of the Customer Data that it collects and processes and for compliance with applicable data protection laws (including laws relating to notification of security incidents) that may apply to the collection, processing and disclosure of Customer Data through the Services.

  8.  ********Links to Third Party Websites and Services****

The Services may contain links to webpages operated by parties other than NexTraq.  We do not control such websites and are not responsible for their contents or the privacy policies or other practices of such websites.  Our inclusion of links to such websites does not imply any endorsement of the material on such websites or any association with their operators.  Further, it is up to you to take precautions to ensure that whatever links you select or software you download (whether by using the Services to access websites or otherwise) is free of such items as viruses, worms, trojan horses, defects and other items of a destructive nature.   Other websites and services may have their own privacy policies, which you will be subject to upon linking to the other third party’s website.  NexTraq strongly recommends that you review the other third party’s terms and policies.

  9.  ********Children’s Privacy****

Our Services are not intended for children under 16 years of age.  No one under age 16 may provide any information to or on the Services.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16.  If you are under 16, do not use or provide any information on our Services or on or through any of its features/register on the Services, use any of the interactive or public comment features of this Services or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use.  If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 16 years of age without verification of parental consent, we will delete the information.  If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under age 16, please contact us at as set forth in the contact section below.

  10.  ********Accessing, Correcting, and Deleting Your Information****

You may choose not to receive marketing email communications from us by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in our marketing emails.  You also may ask us not to send you other marketing communications by contacting us as set forth in the “Contact Us” section below, and we will honor your request.

We aim to maintain our Services in a manner that protects information from accidental or malicious destruction.  Because of this, we may not immediately delete residual copies from our active servers and may not remove information from our backup systems.

Subject to applicable law, you may obtain a copy of personal information we maintain about you or you may request that we delete personal information we maintain about you by contacting us as set forth in the “Contact Us” section below.  To help protect your privacy and maintain security, we will take steps to verify your identity before granting you access to the information.  In addition, if you believe that personal information we maintain about you is inaccurate, subject to applicable law, you may have the right to request that we correct or amend the information by contacting us as set forth in the “Contact Us” section below.

  11.  ********Objection to Processing; Suspension of Procession****

Under applicable law, you may have the right at any time to object to our use of your personal information for any direct marketing purposes, including profiling to the extent it is used for direct marketing.  If we are processing your personal information based on our business interests, you may contact us and object to such processing by asserting that our interests do not override your interests, rights, and freedoms.  You may exercise the rights set out in this paragraph by contacting us as set forth in the “Contact Us” section below.

Under applicable law, you may have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information, if:

  * you believe that the personal information we maintain about you is inaccurate, and you have asked us to verify the accuracy of such information as provided above;
  * you believe that your personal information has been unlawfully processed and you want us to restrict processing rather than erase your information;
  * we no longer need your personal information, but you need us to retain it in order to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim; or
  * you have objected to our processing of your personal information, as permitted under applicable law, and we are considering the grounds of your objection.

  12.  ********Specific Information for California Residents****

California residents are entitled to contact us to request information about whether we have disclosed personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.   California residents may request information about our compliance with this law by contacting us as set forth in the “Contact Us” section below.  California residents may also request at any time that we not sell their personal information to any third party, other than as permitted under applicable law as an exception to such a request.

  13.  ********Compliance and Cooperation with Regulatory Authorities****

We regularly review our compliance with our Privacy Policy.  When we receive formal written complaints, we will contact the person who made the complaint to follow up.  We work with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data if we cannot resolve the matter with our customers directly.  Subject to applicable law, you also have a right to communicate directly with appropriate regulatory authorities if you believe we are in violation of your rights under applicable law.

  14.  ********International Transfers****

Your personal information may be transferred to countries outside of the country in which we collect it.  If we transfer your information to a country outside of the country in which we collect it, we will comply with applicable law, including any requirements related to ensuring that data is transferred with appropriate safeguards.

Specifically, your personal information may be transmitted by NexTraq to our affiliate based in France, the “Manufacture Française des Pneumatiques Michelin” (“Michelin”) who would process your information as data controller for research and development purposes.  Such processing is based on the legitimate interest of the data controller to improve its products and services.  The processed data is essential for such processing and is used by Michelin’s relevant departments and, where applicable, its subcontractors.  Your data may in certain cases be transferred outside the European Union, notably to India.  The transfers within the Michelin Group are framed by the Michelin Group’s Binding Corporate Rules which have been validated by the French Data Protection Authority, the CNIL (available on michelin.com).  The data retention period is limited to 3 years. In accordance with the French Data Protection Act of 6 January 1978 and the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), you can access and obtain copy of your data, object the processing of data for legitimate reasons, and have your data corrected or deleted.  You also have a right to restrict the processing of your data, a right to the portability of your data (in the cases defined by the applicable regulations) and a right to define the fate of your data after your death.  To exercise one of these rights please contact Michelin at the following address privacy.fr@michelin.com.  If your request is unsatisfied, you can also file a complaint with the CNIL on its website www.cnil.fr.

  15.  ********Changes to Privacy Policy****

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time in our sole discretion. If we do make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you as required under applicable law, and we will also indicate the “last modified” date at the top of this page. Please check back often for any updates. Your continued use of our websites or Services after any change in this Privacy Policy is posted and you are notified (if required under applicable law) will constitute your acceptance of such change.

  16.  ********Contact Us****

For additional inquiries about this Privacy Policy, please send us an email at privacy@nextraq.com, or contact us at:

NexTraq LLC

ATTN: Legal, Privacy Counsel

1200 Lake Hearn Drive

Suite 500

Atlanta, GA  30319
